Guide to the Cornell artists and local video programs
Cornell artists and local video programs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell artists and local video programs.
3867
Tompkins County Public Library.
16 cubic ft
Videotapes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
A 3/4" video-cassette of the work of Cornell University artists. Included on the tape are Archie R. Ammons, John A. Hartell, Peter H. Kahn, Stephen F. Poleskie, and Jason L. Seley; interviews by Johnnie Parrish.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
A 3/4" video-cassette of the work of Cornell University artists. Included on the tape are Archie R. Ammons, John A. Hartell, Peter H. Kahn, Stephen F. Poleskie, and Jason L. Seley; interviews by Johnnie Parrish.
Also, videotapes from "Focus on Art" with area artists, and numerous other programs featuring local issues, individuals, and concerns.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Tompkins County Public Library.; Ammons, A. R., 1926-; Hartell, John A., 1902-; Kahn, Peter.; Parrish, Johnnie.; Poleskie, Stephen F.; Seley, Jason, 1919-1983.
Subjects:
Art.; Artists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- VHS videotapes
  - Focus on Art, Alison Mason Kingsbury-Bishop, 1981; 1 (Box 1)
    Also on DVD-524
  - Focus on Art, Corning Glass, Zevi Blum, 1981; 2 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Allen Mooney, Patricia Hartman Lewis, 1981; 3 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Ken Evett, 1982; 4 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, John Hartell, 1982; 5 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Olaf Brauner (24 min.), 1983; 6 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Madeline Minich d'Erny, 1983; 7 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Andrew Gillis, Photographer, 1983; 8 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, H. Peter Kahn, 1983; 9 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Robert Dein Potter, 1983; 10 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Jason Seley, "A Celebration of Sculpture", 1983; 11 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Jack Squier, 1983; 12 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Local Artists at Smithsonian, 1983; 13 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Michael Boyd, 1984; V-9730 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Robert Calkins, 1984; 15 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Harvey Ferdschneider, 1984; 16 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Kumi Korf (30min.), 1984; 17 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Don Queen, 1984; 18 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Janet Braun Reinitz, 1984; 19 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Margaret Kerr Richenberg (27 min.), 1984; 20 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Daphne Sola, Printmaker, 1984; 21 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Hinckley Museum, 1984; 22 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Barbara Page (19 min.), 1985; 23 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Eliot and Steven Porter (22 min.), 1985; 24 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Lagoon Cycle: Helen Meyer Harrison and Newton Harrison (30 min.), 1985; 25 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Order and Enigma (30 min.), 1985; 26 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, John Hartell, 1988; 27 (Box 1)
  - Focus on Art, Steve Poleskie, 1988; 28 (Box 1)
- ¾" videotapes
  - Converstaion on Music, Malcolm Bilson (30:30), 1984; 1 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, John Cooper/Jeff Holm, 1984; 2 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, Florence Flumerfelt (29:30), 1984; 3 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, Karel Husa, 1984; 4 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, Sonya Monosoff, 1984; 5 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, Thomas A. Sokol, 1984; 6 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, James Webster, Neal Zaslow, 1984; 7 (Box 2)
  - Converstaion on Music, Einar Holm, John Cooper (28:31:18), 1985; 8 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Max Black, 1983; 9 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Jorge Luis Borges, 1983; 10 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Ed Marinaro (29:00), 1983; 11 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, William Styron (Sophie's Choice) (29:00), 1983; 12 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Richard S. Dubelman, 1984; 13 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Scott Elledge, 1984; 14 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Howard M. Feinstein, 1984; 15 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Harriet Doerr, 1985; 16 (Box 2)
  - Distinctive Voices, Wole Soyinka, 1985; 1 (Box 3)
  - Distinctive Voices, Ishmael Reed (27:00), 1986; 2 (Box 3)
  - Distinctive Voices, C. Michael Cortis, Atlantic Monthly; William Kennedy (29:00), 3 (Box 3)
  - Distinctive Voices, Mary Hazzard, Fanes McConkey, 4 (Box 3)
  - Distinctive Voices, 5 (Box 3)
  - Distinctive Voices, Wole Soyinka (28:00), 6 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Peregrine Falcon Project at Cornell, Bird Banding in Ithaca (30:00), 1985; 7 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, The Birds (30:01), 1985; 8 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Food Safety (28:35), 1985; 9 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Ozone (28:44), 1985; 10 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Bees/Dyce Lab/Roger Morris, 1986; 11 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Gypsy Moth: Piggy back ride for viral DNA (29:39), 1986; 12 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Hally's Comet, Guests Joe Vevequa and Philip Nicholson (27:54), 1986; 13 (Box 3)
  - Facets: Excursions into Science, Pesticides (30:50), 1986; 14 (Box 3)
  - Focus on Art, Jason Seley, 1980; 15 (Box 3)
  - Focus on Art, Cornell Artists, 1980; 15 (Box 3)
  - Focus on Art, A.K.M. Bishop and Archie Ammons, 1981; 16 (Box 3)
  - Focus on Art, D.H. Dillingham, Upstairs Gallery, Sheraton, 1981; 1 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, David Findley and Splendors of Sophites, 1981; 2 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Kumi Korf and Gary Wojuik Rick Burns, Ithaca House Gallery and Johnson Museum, 1981; 3 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Cornell Artists II, 1981; 4 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Corning Museum American Glass (17:00), 1981; 5 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Lessons in Print (39:58), 1981; 6 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Will Barnet, 1982; 7 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Kenneth Evett, 1982; 8 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, John Hartell, 1982; 9 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Allen Mooney, Patricia Hartman-Lewis, 1982; 10 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Robert Richenberg, 1982; 11 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Robert Smithson, 1982; 12 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Art of Book Illustration: Donald E. Eddy and H. Peter Kahn, 1982; 13 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Golden Day, Silver Night: American Landscape, 1982; 14 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Olaf M. Brauner, 1983; 15 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Robert Dein, 1983; 16 (Box 4)
  - Focus on Art, Madeline Minich d'Erney, 1983; 1 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Kenneth Evett, 1983; 2 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Andrew Gillis, 1983; 3 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, H. Peter Kahn (31:00), 1983; 4 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Jason Seley, 1983; 5 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Jack L. Squier, 1983; 6 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Ancient Glass, Corning Museum, 1983; 7 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Local Artists at the Smithsonian (28:30 min), 1983; 8 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Ten Years of Collecting: H.F. Johnson Museum (30:30), 1983; 9 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Michael Boyd, 1984; 10 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Janet Braun-Reinitz (32:00), 1984; 11 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Robert G. Calkins (29:35), 1984; 12 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Harvey Ferdschneider, 1984; 13 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Kumi Korf (30:20), 1984; 14 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Donald Queen, 1984; 15 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Margaret Kerr Richenberg, 1984; 16 (Box 5)
  - Focus on Art, Daphne Sola (27:07), 1984; 1 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, John Szarkowski, 1984; 2 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, DeWitt Historical Society of Tompkins County (28:30), 1984; 3 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, John Hartell (30:40), 1985; 4 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Steve Poleskie (30:07) (2 copies), 1985; 5-6 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Eliot and Steve Porter (22:00:27), 1985; 7 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Lagoon Cycle: Helen Mayer Harrison and Newton Harrison (26:40), 1985; 8 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Waterworks by Barbara Page (19:00:07), 1985; 9 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Order and Enigma, 1989; 10 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Art of Fine Prints I and II, 11-12 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Dora Donovan, 13 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Printmaking I and II, 14-15 (Box 6)
  - Focus on Art, Vitrix Glass Studio, 16 (Box 6)
  - Studio Portraits, Annie Campbell (clayworker), 1985; 1 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Tobias Dean (woodworker) (31:20), 1985; 2 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Jonathan Kline (black-ash basket maker) (30:30), 1985; 3 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Mike Lanieu (tailor), 1985; 4 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, William Marsh (29:59), 1985; 5 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Nancy Medsker (29:30), 1985; 6 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Chet Slastri (30:30), 1985; 7 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Ba Stopha (clay artist) (30:30), 1985; 8 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Renate Ferro (printmaker), 1986; 9 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Ashley Miller (marbelling), 1986; 10 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Durand Van Doran (blacksmith) (26:54), 1986; 11 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Liz Garrison, 12 (Box 7)
  - Studio Portraits, Michael Rambo, 13 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany, Complete Slush, 1986; 14 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany, "Faces in a Famine" (51:00), 15 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany, Ithaca Festival (49:40), 1987; 16 (Box 7)
  - Miscellany, "The Magic of Christmas Downtown" (43:00), 1 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Odyssey Story Tellers: Rick Rogers (25:00), 2 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Tin Can Fantasy Factory: "King That Could", 3 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Tin Can Fantasy Factory: "Pebbles, Rocks and Skipping Stones" (39:59), 4 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Tin Can Fantasy Factory: "The Talking Bird," "Androcles and the Lion" (61:00), 5 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Wild Washer Women Program 1 (kids), 6 (Box 8)
  - Miscellany, Wild Washer Women Program 2, 7 (Box 8)